I have often wondered about the people
who settled the land here first.
To come to Iceland and experience the nature
as dramatic as it is.
To settle, live here and establish yourself
in a way so that it’s possible to survive.
It would have definitely been spectacular to see
all the waterfalls, the mountains, the geothermal areas...
but I can’t imagine that it would have been easy.
I have never needed to settle land, or cultivate food
to survive or provide for my family.
Not in that way
But I have gone through other difficulties in life.
I think that that is common for most people
Maybe similar to what Ingólfur Arnarson and Hrafna-Flókia
and their people went through thousands of years ago.
My name is Brynjólfur Víðir Ólafsson
and I’m a member of the
Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints
I grew up in Iceland in Hafnarfjörður
and I was accustomed to playing in the lava
when I was little
and went out on Herjólfsgata,
and in high school I took courses in mountaineering
I never really thought about how great the nature was
in Iceland, and how blessed I was to enjoy it.
Since then I have lived in many different places,
traveled far and wide
it was last summer that we went to Iceland
and got the opportunity to travel around a bit
and enjoy the nature once again
then I realized how lucky I really had been when I grew up
to have the Icelandic nature just as my playground.
I think that that is similar to the Gospel,
to my faith in God and Jesus Christ
that which you grow up with - I had it as a part of my
childhood and was used to going to church
and learning about Jesus, praying with my family,
and reading the in the scriptures
It was something that I maybe hadn’t thought a lot about,
but to the same extent
when I got older and went through life’s raging sea,
have a family and travel between places
one starts to get all sorts of thoughts and difficulties,
"Am I enough for my family? Am I doing enough
for my kids to raise them properly and be there for them
and show them love and concern?"
It was similar to the Icelandic nature,
a new view of my faith in Jesus Christ.
It has been something that I have gotten to rediscover
in my grown-up years.
I have often gotten to look to Christ
and put my faith in Him
and search in the scriptures, and have received answers
to those challenges that I have gone through
I have received guidance to help me to overcome
those challenges and grow through that process.
If you are searching for something and don’t know what it is
some purpose in life or
or you feel like you are lacking something
then my advice would be to learn to pray,
talk with God,
and learn to recognize those feelings
that he uses to talk to you.
No matter how we look to Him,
if we are sincere in heart, we can talk to Him
and He listens to us and answers us and guides us
He is ready to do that in order to help us realize
what this life is all about
Often it’s not in the way that I am expecting or
exactly when I am expecting, but
it’s unbelievable how when I look back on
the most difficult times in my  life,
I see that there is a larger purpose
and that there is a plan
and maybe more than I could see originally.
I know that God is with us
and He loves us
and He wants us to be able to return back to Him,
and He is ready to help us to do that.